easypeasyandfun.com 2019-05-12

# Privacy Policy - Easy Peasy and Fun

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://www.easypeasyandfun.com (Easy Peasy and Fun). The website is owned by Andreja Vučajnk s.p, Slovenia. We value your privacy and understand that your privacy is of critical importance.

This Privacy Policy describes what information we collect from you via the website and how we use and disclose such information.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Email for Newsletter

**Short:** If you choose to receive email updates from Easy Peasy and Fun, you can change your mind and unsubscribe at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link that is included in every email. We won’t sell your data an will keep it secure.

**Detailed:** Easy Peasy and Fun offers a newsletter service, where we send 1-3 weekly updates to your email address. The subscription to our newsletter is voluntary and we only collect your email address for the purpose of sending out newsletter communication. If you subscribe to our newsletter service you will get regular email updates with our arty and crafty ideas and what we are up to (or on occasion curated ideas from other creative blogs and websites).

We use MailerLite to manage our email marketing subscriber list and to send emails to our subscribers. MailerLite is a third-party provider, which may process your data using industry standard technologies to help us monitor and improve our newsletter.

MailerLite’s privacy policy is available at <https://www.mailerlite.com/privacy-policy>.

You can unsubscribe from our newsletter by clicking on the unsubscribe link provided at the end of each newsletter.

### Cookies

**What is a cookie?**

A cookie is a file containing an identifier, a string of letters and numbers. The webs server sends the file to the browser and the browser stores the file. The file is then set back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

Some cookies will expire at the end of the user session, when the user closes the browser. Persistent cookies will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until their expiry date, unless user deletes them before the expiry date.

Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

What do we use the cookies for?

  * authentication (to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate the website)
  * personalization (if you so choose)
  * security
  * advertising (to display advertising and serve ads relevant to you)
  * analysis (to help us analyse the use and performance of our website and services)

We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

#### Cookies when leaving comments on the website

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. Leaving your email address in comments section is optional.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Accounts on website

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Advertising

Easy Peasy and Fun is affiliated with Mediavine for the purpose of running ads on this website.

### Affiliate Links

We sometimes use affiliate links to recommend products.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

## Who we share your data with

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## Your contact information

You can contact us at info@easypeasyandfun.com (by contacting us, you give us permission to use your email address and data provided in the email to communicate with you).

Effective as of May 25, 2018
